https://www.outdoorcanada.ca/privacy-policy/

FishingFishing
How Chris Johnston became the first Canadian to win a Bassmaster Elite eventOutdoor Canada’s 2020 holiday gift guide for anglers and hunters9 of Western Canada’s top fishing spots from TV’s Fishing the Wild West
Fishing Hot Spots
Fishing Tips & Tactics
Fly Fishing
Ice Fishing
Fishing Times
All Fishing Posts
HuntingHunting
Outdoor Canada’s 2020 holiday gift guide for anglers and huntersHunting late-season Canada geese? Try these expert scouting strategiesHunter and chef Michael Hunter shares wild-game cooking tips from his new book
Hunting Hot Spots
Hunting Tips
Firearms
Bowhunting
Big Game
Upland
Waterfowl
Small Game
Hunting Times
All Hunting Posts
SkillsSkills
12 must-have items for your fishing and hunting first-aid kit3 ways to be tick safe during your outdoor adventuresHow to rescue someone who’s fallen through the ice
GearGear
Outdoor Canada’s 2020 holiday gift guide for anglers and huntersThe year’s best new merino wool apparel for hunters and anglers12 must-have items for your fishing and hunting first-aid kit
ATVs
Boats
Gadgets
Guns
Optics
Tackle
All Gear Posts
NewsNews
How Chris Johnston became the first Canadian to win a Bassmaster Elite eventOutdoor Canada’s 2020 holiday gift guide for anglers and huntersHunter and chef Michael Hunter shares wild-game cooking tips from his new book
RecipesRecipes
Recipe & video: Scrumptious duck schnitzel with a hearty potato sauceRecipe & video: Scrumptious smoked-steelhead pizza—from scratch!Recipe & video: Tender goose with Morocco-inspired spices
BlogsBlogs
Blue Fish Radio: The Great Lakes are under threat from chemicals—againWhy fish might sometimes just be “playing” with our baitsWhy single-action ice-fishing reels are tops for trout, panfish and walleye
Blue Fish Radio
Canadian Bowhunter
Field Findings
On the Water Online
ContestsContestsEnter to Win 1 of 2 Browning Firearms12 of the year’s best Canadian outdoor adventure photosEnter Outdoor Canada’s 10th annual photo contest!
Shop
Subscriptions
Subscribe
Renew
Give a Gift
Digital Subscription Login
Subscription Account Login
Contact Us
Privacy Policy
Who we are
Our website address is: https://www.outdoorcanada.ca. We are owned by Outdoor Group Media Ltd. and our web services are provided by OP Media Group Ltd.
What personal data we collect and why we collect it
Marketing Campaigns
We use email marketing to communicate with customers and potential customers from time to time. All email lists and campaigns are “opt-in” meaning we will not send you these sorts of emails unless you indicated that you wish to receive them during signup or other interactions on our website.
We may send you “system” emails, such as password reset requests or payment notifications/receipts even if you have not opted-in to email marketing list. This is due to your purchase of a magazine subscription with us, whether it is in print or digital format, or both.
All marketing emails sent by us will include an unsubscribe link in the footer of the email. Emails sent to you may also include standard tracking, including open and click activities. We use ActiveCampaign for email marketing.
We use social media and web advertising campaigns. These service providers use cookies on our sites and/or pixel tracking to serve ads across the different platforms.
Google Ad Manager (privacy policy | opt out)
AvantLink (privacy policy)
Twitter (privacy policy | opt out)
Facebook (privacy policy | opt out)
Magazine Subscriptions
CDS Global collects information for the purposes of subscription order processing and thus email preferences for ActiveCampaign and Imirus, and credit card payments through Moneris. This info is imported to CDS Global’s database to manage magazine subscriptions. Full name and mailing address are mandatory fields for the purposes of mailing out magazine subscriptions.
Moneris is used to process credit card payments. Subscription orders processed online are connected to Moneris, Canada’s leading processor of Debit and credit card payments, in order to process the credit card payments. To comply with accounting, auditing and legal requirements, we keep data on financial transactions until a particular year’s audit has been completed. British Columbia Magazine is an audited magazine.
Any subscriptions, single copy magazine sales, books and other merchandise that are on OP Media Group’s store are processed via Shopify. The link to OP Media Group’s Shopify Privacy Policy is:
https://shop.opmediagroup.ca/pages/privacy-policy
If you have a digital subscription to our magazine, you will receive email correspondence and access to your digital subscriptions via CDS Global.
Links to the privacy policies of the most common services have been included below:
ActiveCampaign: https://www.activecampaign.com/privacy-policy/
Moneris: https://www.moneris.com/en/Privacy-Policy
Shopify: https://www.shopify.com/legal/privacy
Comments
We use the Facebook comments plugin. It allows you to leave comments on using your Facebook account. You can choose to share your comment activity on Facebook as well.
When visitors leave comments on the site we collect the data shown in the comments form, and also the visitor’s IP address and browser user agent string to help spam detection.
An anonymized string created from your email address (also called a hash) may be provided to the Gravatar service to see if you are using it. The Gravatar service privacy policy is available here: https://automattic.com/privacy/. After approval of your comment, your profile picture is visible to the public in the context of your comment.
Media
If you upload images to the website for our photo contest, you should avoid uploading images with embedded location data (EXIF GPS) included. Visitors to the website can download and extract any location data from images on the website.
For the purposes of entering our photo contests, we request JPEG files only.
Online Forms
We generally collect personally identifiable information with your specific knowledge and consent. For example, when you enter a sweepstakes or contest, complete a survey, make a purchase on our Shopify, subscribe to our publication, register for certain services, or register and/or set up an account/profile to access, visit and/or use certain portions of the Service, or the Service as a whole, you may be provided, or required to choose, a password and/or User ID, and you may provide a credit, debit, or charge card number, or other payment information, as well as your name, telephone number(s), email and/or street address, and other personally identifiable information. Other information such as your age, gender, an avatar, and the number for your mobile or other device may also be requested. In addition, you may be asked to send us similar information via messaging (e.g., email, SMS, MMS, or other technologies).
In the event that you subscribe to our publication online via QFIE, the “Prefix” is a mandatory field in which you would enter your title, with those titles being “Mr”, “Mrs”, “Ms”, “Dr & Mrs”, and so forth. This is considered to be Personally Identifiable Information under linkable information as the “Prefix” would be used to determine your gender. The Gender field would be stored in QuickFill under your subscription account. The “Prefix” is a mandatory field set by the Circulation Manager.
Cookies
If you leave a comment on our site you may opt-in to saving your name, email address and website in cookies. These are for your convenience so that you do not have to fill in your details again when you leave another comment. These cookies will last for one year.
If you have an account and you log in to this site, we will set a temporary cookie to determine if your browser accepts cookies. This cookie contains no personal data and is discarded when you close your browser.
When you log in, we will also set up several cookies to save your login information and your screen display choices. Login cookies last for two days, and screen options cookies last for a year. If you select “Remember Me”, your login will persist for two weeks. If you log out of your account, the login cookies will be removed.
If you edit or publish an article, an additional cookie will be saved in your browser. This cookie includes no personal data and simply indicates the post ID of the article you just edited. It expires after 1 day.
Embedded content from other websites
Articles on this site may include embedded content (e.g. videos, images, articles, etc.). Embedded content from other websites behaves in the exact same way as if the visitor has visited the other website.
These websites may collect data about you, use cookies, embed additional third-party tracking, and monitor your interaction with that embedded content, including tracing your interaction with the embedded content if you have an account and are logged in to that website.
Analytics
We use Google Analytics for tracking visitors and aggregating information about the traffic to our websites. The Google Analytics privacy policy can be found here:  https://policies.google.com/privacy. You can learn more about how to opt-out of tracking in Google Analytics here.
Who we share your data with
We use third-party services (data processors) across our sites. The extent to which your data is shared with these providers depends on your use of our services, and we list the specific third-parties in use (with links to their privacy policies) in the sections below.
Each third-party provider has been vetted by our security team to ensure that privacy policies and practices meet or exceed the same levels of compliance and standards that we follow. Where appropriate and available, we hold additional signed Data Privacy Agreements with these companies as an additional layer of accountability in order to help ensure your data is safe and secure.
We disclose potentially personally-identifying and personally-identifying information only to our employees, contractors and affiliated organizations that (i) need to know that information in order to process it on our behalf or to provide services, and (ii) that have agreed, in writing, not to disclose it to others. Some of those employees, contractors and affiliated organizations may be located outside of your home country; by using our websites and services, you consent to the transfer of such information to them. We will not rent or sell potentially personally-identifying and personally-identifying information to anyone.
Plugin authors who inform us of features that are not potentially GDPR compliant suggest disabling those features to which we comply. In the event that the plugin authors have not disclosed such information, we remove and disable the features until further notice from the plugin authors.
We may be required to disclose an individual’s personal information in response to a lawful request by public authorities, including to meet national security or law enforcement requirements.
If we ever were to engage in any onward transfers of your data with third parties for a purpose other than which it was originally collected or subsequently authorized, we would provide you with an opt-out choice to limit the use and disclosure of your personal data.
Business Transfers
If Outdoor Canada, or substantially all of its assets, were acquired, or in the unlikely event that Outdoor Canada goes out of business or enters bankruptcy, user information would be one of the assets that is transferred or acquired by a third party. You acknowledge that such transfers may occur, and that any acquirer of Outdoor Canada may continue to use your personal information as set forth in this policy.
How long we retain your data
User and event data stored by Google Analytics are retained for 26 months.
For users that register on our website (if any), we store the personal information they provide in their user profile. All users can see, edit, or delete their personal information at any time. Website administrators can also see and edit that information. Once you have registered on our website as a magazine subscriber, we keep your account information in our subscription database as long as it is required by the government for auditing purposes. If your subscription is cancelled, your account is marked as such and you will no longer receive any offers.
What rights you have over your data
If you have an account on this site, or have left comments, you can request to receive an exported file of the personal data we hold about you, including any data you have provided to us. You can also request that we erase any personal data we hold about you. This does not include any data we are obliged to keep for administrative, legal, or security purposes.
Visitor comments may be checked through an automated spam detection service.
How we protect your data
See wordpress.org/about/security for details on the security of the WordPress core itself.
We follow all WordPress Code Standards in the plugins that we use and we regularly update our plugins and code.
All staff only have access to systems that are directly required to complete the functions of their job. We use dual factor authentication for all Google-related services that we use, and automatically log all staff activity through the software that we use.
We only use third-party services that adhere to the highest levels of privacy and security practices to the best of our knowledge.
What Data Breach Procedures We Have In Place
Should any event occur where customer data has been lost, stolen, or potentially compromised, our policy is to alert our customers via email, telephone, or lettermail. We will also report such incident to any required data protection authority. We will work closely with any customers affected to determine the actions needed to rectify the data breach and how to avoid any similar event in the future.
Contact Us
For more information about our privacy practices, if you have questions, or if you would like to make a complaint, please contact us by e-mail at info@outdoorgroupmedia.com or by mail using the details provided below:
Outdoor Group Media
[Re: Privacy Compliance Officer]
802 – 1166 Alberni Street Vancouver British Columbia CA V6E 3Z3
Although most changes are likely to be minor, Outdoor Canada may change its Privacy Policy from time to time, and in Outdoor Canada’s sole discretion. Outdoor Canada encourages visitors to frequently check this page for any changes to its Privacy Policy. If you have a outdoorcanada.ca account, you might also receive an alert informing you of these changes. Your continued use of this site after any change in this Privacy Policy will constitute your acceptance of such change.
Latest Posts
How Chris Johnston became the first Canadian to win a Bassmaster Elite eventOutdoor Canada’s 2020 holiday gift guide for anglers and huntersHunting late-season Canada geese? Try these expert scouting strategiesHunter and chef Michael Hunter shares wild-game cooking tips from his new book9 of Western Canada’s top fishing spots from TV’s Fishing the Wild WestSign Up for Our Newsletter!
You will be sent an opt-in email to confirm that you would like to receive emails from us. By signing up for our newsletter, you agree to our Privacy Policy and Terms of Service. You also agree to receive email updates on new posts and offers. You can unsubscribe at any time by clicking on the "Unsubscribe" link at the bottom of every email.
Fishing
Fishing Hot Spots
Fishing Tips & Tactics
Fly Fishing
Ice Fishing
Fishing Times
All Fishing Posts
Hunting
Subscribe to Outdoor Canada's Newsletter!
And keep up-to-date with Canada's fishing and hunting authority!
You will be sent an opt-in email to confirm that you would like to receive emails from us.
Send this to a friend
